The damage wrought from last year's tornado extends all the way here.
（アリーシャ）去年の竜巻の
被害が ここまでとは…
（ボルタ）
向こうに 小さな集落がありました
There's a small settlement over yonder.
（タオ）頼めば 一夜の宿を―
If we ask around, we can probably find someone to put us up for the night.
提供してくれる家も
見つかるとは思いますが
There's no need.
（アリーシャ）
いや 我らが押しかければ
迷惑をかけるだけだ
I don't want to add to their burdens.
We'll camp outside.
野宿でよい
This is fine for one night.
（アリーシャ）
一夜の寝床としては十分だ
（ボルタ）どうしました？ 姫様
What's the matter, Princess?
Volta, this is an ancient ruin.
ボルタ ここは遺跡のようだ
Could it be from the Era of Asgard?
（ボルタ）
アスガード時代のものでしょうか？
（アリーシャ）
うん… どうだろう？
I'm not sure.
（ガネット）これは…
This is...
That's a Shepherd, right?!
（ボルタ）
“導師”ですよね？ これ
クレムが これを見たら
きっと 大はしゃぎですよ
Clem would flip out if she saw this.
「天遺(てんい)見聞録」に
書かれてあることは―
She's convinced that everything written in the Celestial Record is true.
全部 本当のことなんだって
力説してましたからね
クレムに「天遺見聞録」を
勧めたのは 私だ
I'm the one who recommended the Celestial Record to her.
（ガネット）すると 姫様も
信じておられるのですか？
Then you believe too, Princess?
That Shepherds exist?
導師の存在を
もし いるのなら
私も会ってみたいものだよ
If they do exist, I'd love to meet one someday.
導師に
A real-life Shepherd.
Listen up!
（クレム）はーい！ 聖剣祭の
剣の試練に参加希望の人は―
Those interested in taking the Trial of the Blade can sign up inside the Sanctuary!
聖堂の中で
受付を行っていまーす！
Clem!
（タオ）クレム！
The princess requests your presence.
姫様がお呼びだぞ
I'll cover your post.
ここは 私が代わる
（クレム）
あっ お願いします タオさん
Thank you, Tao.
（タオ）お前らの中で―
Do any of you dare to undertake the Trial of the Blade?!
剣の試練に
挑戦したいってやつはいるかー！
（クレム）お呼びでしょうか
You wished to see me?
Isn't your father a physician in Guriel?
（マルトラン）お前の叔父が
グリエルで医師を務めていたな？
（クレム）はい マルトラン先生
Yes, Lady Maltran.
（マルトラン）
やはり クレムが適任であろう
Then Clem is the perfect choice.
うっ あの… あっ…
Pardon me...
先ほど 天文学者の
ドレイク教授が―
Just a while ago, Drake the astronomer came to report the discovery of a strange cloud, or rather, mist.
奇妙な雲というか
霧を発見したと報告に参られた
The wind does not move it.
それは 風が吹いても流れず
雨が降っても消えず―
The rain does not disperse it.
It simply hovers over one location.
ずっと 上空に
とどまっているというのだ
（マルトラン）その場所というのが
どうも グリエルらしい
And that location seems to be Guriel.
That's why you summoned me?
それで 私を
（アリーシャ）ここ数年
ハイランドは異常気象続きで―
As you know, the weather has been unstable in Hyland for several years now.
It has affected crops throughout the land.
各地に 農作物への被害も出ている
不調などを訴える者がいないか
調べてきてほしい
I want you to go to Guriel and see if anyone reports anything unusual.
（クレム）はい 分かりました
Yes, ma'am.
I'm counting on you.
（アリーシャ）よろしく頼む
（クレム）では さっそく
I'll leave immediately.
姫様
Princess...
姫様から頂いた「天遺見聞録」―
I've grown quite fond of the
Celestial Record that you gave me.
今では 私の宝物です
I'm glad you like it.
気に入ってくれて 私もうれしい
（アリーシャ）どういうことです！
Are you mad?!
You want to conscript the youth who come to the Sacred Blade Festival?!
聖剣祭のために訪れた
若者たちから―
徴兵するなんて！
That's a terrible idea, Chancellor Mathia!
それは あまりに暴論です！
マティア軍機卿
If I may, Princess.
（ナタエル）お待ちくだされ 殿下
If the outbreak in neighboring Marlind is contagious,
it is only right to dispatch the army.
隣町 マーリンドで
発生した疾病が―
流行病の疑いがあるのであれば―
軍の派遣は 当然のことかと
What does that have to do
with conscripting soldiers?
軍の派遣と 兵の補強とでは
話が違います
Everything, of course.
（バルトロ）いや 違わない
If we need more troops for public safety,
where do we get them?
もし 治安部隊の
派遣ともなれば―
どこから 兵を割くというのです？
You should take the initiative.
Find and recruit patriotic youths.
（バルトロ）殿下が 率先して
若者たちから―
憂国の士を
募るべきではないですかな？
To serve under you.
王女の名のもとに
（アリーシャ）なるほど
I see.
So that was your plan all along.
もともと その思惑があって
聖剣祭の開催に賛同したのですね
That's why you agreed to hold the Sacred Blade Festival.
I say this as member of the royal family:
王族の１人として 申し上げます
聖剣祭は 決して
戦争の道具にはしません
The Sacred Blade Festival will not be used as a tool of war.
The mist has gotten thicker.
（アリーシャ）
霧が濃くなったとは…
どういうことだ？
Why is that?
（ドレイク）分かりませぬ
I cannot say.
But Princess...
（ドレイク）ですが 姫様―
霧は 以前より増して不気味に―
The mist has become more ominous.
In fact, it seems downright malevolent.
さらに禍々(まがまが)しくなっているように
感じます
私には 何か よからぬ
前触れのような気がしてなりませぬ
I can't help but feel this is an omen of some kind.
（アリーシャ）
クレムの後を追って―
Can you follow Clem and head for Guriel?
グリエルへ
向かってもらえるだろうか
（ドレイク）承知いたしました
Right away, my lady.
（アリーシャ）ガネット
クレムがグリエルへ出立して―
Gannet, how long has it been since Clem left?
どれくらい たつ？
Roughly two weeks.
（ガネット）
かれこれ ２週間ほどかと
遅すぎる
And still no word.
（タオ）姫様
（アリーシャ）あっ
Princess.
あ… タオ どうした？
What's the matter, Tao?
Who are you?!
（タオ）何だ お前たちは！
ふんっ
（ルナール）なっ… くうっ
（アリーシャ）はあっ！
（ルナール）うっ… くっ ぬあっ
誰の差し金だ？
Who put you up to this?
（女性）そこまでだ 引け
Enough. Retreat.
Boss, I can still do this.
（ルナール）頭領 俺は まだ…
You're no match for her.
（女性）お前のかなう相手じゃない
（ルナール）クッヒヒヒヒ…
（アリーシャ）はっ
You're pretty good, Princess.
やるねえ お姫さん
（ルナール）
クッヒャヒャヒャヒャヒャッ
（女性）
なぜ とどめを刺さなかった？
Why didn't you finish him?
十分 刺せたはずだ
You had plenty of chances.
Was it because of your so-called integrity?
それは 偽りの清廉さか？
Or...
それとも…
What do you want? Answer me!
（アリーシャ）
何の話だ？ 答えろ！
You're going to Guriel?
（マルトラン）
グリエルに行ってみるだと？
I'm worried about Clem.
（アリーシャ）クレムが心配です
（マルトラン）行くというのなら
それは 私の役目だ
Then I should be the one to go.
Clem is my pupil, after all.
クレムは 私の弟子だからな
No.
（アリーシャ）いえ 先生には―
I need you to oversee the preparations for the Sacred Blade Festival.
このまま 聖剣祭の準備を
進めていただきます
I don't want to postpone it,
even for a short time.
一時(いっとき)であれ
中断したくありません
Why are you so determined to hold the festival this year?
なぜ そこまで
聖剣祭に こだわる？
本当に この聖剣を引き抜く者が
現れると信じているのか？
Do you honestly believe that someone will be able to extract the Sacred Blade?
The one who extracts the sword guarded by the Lady of the Lake will be the Shepherd.
（アリーシャ）湖の乙女が守る
聖剣を抜いた者が 導師になる
It's no more than a legend.
これは あくまで伝承
I just don't want this one ray of hope that has begun to shine on Ladylake to fade.
私は ただ―
このレディレイクに芽生え始めた
明るい兆しを―
絶やしたくないだけです
（ボルタ）クレムのやつ
遺跡探検に夢中だったりして
Clem must be having a grand time checking out the ruins.
The ruins?
遺跡探検？
Oh, didn't you know, Tao?
あれ？ タオは聞いてない？
グリエルには レディレイクの
遺跡にも劣らない―
Guriel has ancient underground waterways that rival the ruins in Ladylake.
古代の地下水路がある
（タオ）そうなのですか
Is that so?
She used to brag about always exploring them as a child.
（ボルタ）子どもの頃から よく
探検しに行ったって 自慢してたな
If that's all she's doing,
she's going to get it from me.
（タオ）ったく
そんなことだったら承知しないぞ
（アリーシャ）
それなら それでよい
As long as she's okay.
That's enough for me.
無事なら
Masks, everyone.
（アリーシャ）みんなも
Clem used to say that the green clusters here were as pretty as jewels.
クレムから “緑の房が
宝石のように美しい”と―
聞いていたのだが
Even so, I don't think they'd make for a good souvenir for Maltran.
（タオ）
これでは マルトラン様に―
土産を持ち帰るどころじゃ
ありませんね
Princess Alisha!
アリーシャ様！
Don't pick them!
（少女）ダメだよ とっちゃ！
（アリーシャ）あっ
（少女）むーっ！
（タオ）すまない
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to...
そういうつもりじゃ…
Please forgive us.
（アリーシャ）許してくれ
We have no intention of taking what's yours.
決して そなたのものを
奪おうとしたわけではない
I don't recognize you. You must not be from around here.
（男性）見慣れない顔だな
よそ者か？
Such insolence! Do you know who you're talking to?!
（ボルタ）
失礼な！ このお方を 誰と…
（アリーシャ）身分などよい
It's fine.
I want to ask you something.
（アリーシャ）そなたに聞きたい
How long has that mist been there?
あの霧は いつから
あの場所にあるのだ？
It only became obvious recently, but it's been there a long time.
（男性）目に入るようになったのは
最近だが―
もう 随分 前から…
When we noticed, it was just there.
いや 気付いた時には
あの場所にあった
It was just there?
（アリーシャ）
気付いたら あの場所に？
Here, miss!
（少女）お姉ちゃん これ
（アリーシャ）あっ
はい！
For you!
Thank you.
（アリーシャ）ありがとう
（少女）エヘヘッ
First, let's check in at the guard post.
（アリーシャ）まずは
警備隊の屯所へ顔を出すとしよう
クレムも立ち寄ったはずだ
Clem will have gone there too.
After checking around town, Clem...
（兵士）クレムさんなら
色々と町を見回ったあと…
（兵士のせき込み）
（アリーシャ）あっ 大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
（兵士）すみません
（兵士のせき込み）
Pardon me.
（兵士）
クレムさんは“北の樹海のほうへ
行く”と出たきりです
Clem headed for the woodlands in the north and has yet to return.
Up north? That's in the vicinity of the mist.
（アリーシャ）北というと
霧の立ちこもるほうだな
Indeed, it is.
（兵士）はい 姫様
Just what is that mist?
（アリーシャ）
あの霧は 何なのだ？
We don't know.
（兵士）分かりません
It was just there, and before we knew it, it grew to that size.
気付いた時には あの場所にあって
知らない間に あの大きさに
We've gone several times to observe it more closely,
but we've never noticed anything unusual.
（兵士）これまで 何度か
見に行ったのですが―
特に変わった様子は
ありませんでした
Let me ask you this:
１つ 聞きたい
そなたは この町の様子を
どう思う？
How do you feel about the situation in this town?
It's so lifeless.
（アリーシャ）
それにしても 活気がない
Tao, please stay here.
（アリーシャ）
タオ お前は ここに残ってくれ
このまま 町の散策を続けてほしい
I want you to continue looking around town.
Understood. What about you?
（タオ）分かりました 姫様は？
（アリーシャ）北へ
I'm going north.
樹海へ行く
To the woodlands.
This is...
これは…
The mist... It's moving!
霧が 動いている！？
クレム！
Clem!
Princess Alisha?
アリーシャ様？
Clem! Behind you!
（ガネット･ボルタ）
クレム！ 後ろー！
アリーシャ様！
Princess Alisha!
（アリーシャ）
早く ここを離れるぞ！
We must get away now!
But Drake is still down there!
（クレム）
でも ドレイク教授が まだ下に
He's what?!
（アリーシャ）この下？
He was going to find out about the Earthpulse!
（クレム）“地脈の正体を知る
絶好の機会だ”と
Earthpulse?
（アリーシャ）地脈… あっ
Princess Alisha!
（ボルタ･ガネット）
アリーシャ様！
上で 何か起こっているのか？
くっ…
What's happening up there?
At this rate, the town will be swallowed up.
（アリーシャ）このまま行くと
町が飲まれてしまう
どうすれば…
What do we do?
According to the professor, the world is connected by something called the Earthpulse.
（クレム）
教授が言ってました
“世界は 地脈でつながっている”
Natural energy turning into the Earthpulse is what protects the world's equilibrium.
“自然の力が
地脈となって循環することで―”
“世界の均衡が保たれている”
But now, that equilibrium is broken.
“今は その均衡が崩れている”と
Long ago, man ruled this land...
（クレム･ドレイク）人は
かつて この地をつかさどる―
...and walked the path together in reverence with things unseen.
目には見えないものを崇(あが)め
共に歩んできた
（ドレイク）人は 人のみで
存続してきたわけではない
Man has not existed alone.
This generation is paying for the arrogance of forgetting that.
それを忘れた おごりが
この時代に降り注いでいる
That is what I believe.
そう 私は考えている
もし 地脈を
見つけることができれば―
If I can find the Earthpulse,
perhaps I can discover its secret.
その秘密が分かるかもしれない
（ボルタ）うわっ うわあああ！
（ガネット）ボルタァァァ！
Volta!
（アリーシャ）ガネット！
Gannet!
ボルタ… ガネット…
Volta... Gannet...
（クレム）アリーシャ様！
Princess Alisha!
Please let me off!
Otherwise, we'll be overtaken!
私を降ろしてください！
このままでは追いつかれる！
（アリーシャ）ならない
（クレム）アリーシャ様！
We won't.
Princess Alisha!
We won't!
（アリーシャ）ならん！
I won't let that happen!
そんなことは 許さない！
I shall open the portal of chaos with you.
（サイモン）
お前で 混沌(こんとん)の扉を開こう
What's happening?!
何だ？
一体 何が起きているのだ？
（ルナール）
クッハハハハ… ハハハハ…！
This is great!
面白い
This is so much fun!
面白いねえー！
Who are you?
（アリーシャ）お前は…
（ルナール）キヒャヒャヒャ…
ハハハハッ！
You won't get in the way of my main course!
こいつは 俺様の
メインディッシュなんでね！
（ルナール）キャアーッ！
（アリーシャ）
夢でも見ているのか？ 私は
Is this a dream?
（アリーシャ）
どうなっているんだ？ 一体
What's going on?!
（ルナール）ヒャハハハハハッ！
ヒーッ ヒーッ ヒャーハーッ！
Clem...
クレム？
Clem... No...
まさか… そんな！
Clem! Clem!
クレム！ クレム！
Answer me, Clem!
返事をしろ！ クレム！
（ルナール）ヒャハハッ
It cooled down.
冷めたわ
（ルナール）ああん？
Why?
（アリーシャ）
なぜだ… クレム…
Clem...
Gannet...
ガネット… ボルタ…
Volta...
Miss...
お姉ちゃん
We'll ride upon the wind to follow
Your path leading far off into the distance
The answers we seek won't be easy to find
We set out knowing that from the start
We wander endlessly to leave behind records of our dream
It's worth it if it widens our map of the world
Resound, O song of the wind
Should we forgo sight, the voices of our hearts will push us forwards
We always aim ever higher
Carry, O song of the wind
Should we go without hearing, the voices of our hearts will gush forth
Emitting a dazzling radiance
Your azure melody rings true